Get Some.
Tropic Thunder is a action, comedy, adventure film directed by Ben Stiller.
A group of self-absorbed actors set out to make
the most expensive war film ever.
After ballooning costs force the studio to cancel the movie, the frustrated director refuses to stop
shooting, leading his cast into the jungles of Southeast Asia, where they encounter real bad guys.
Tugg Speedman, played by Ben Stiller.
Kirk Lazarus, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Jeff Portnoy, played by Jack Black.
Kevin Sandusky, played by Jay Baruchel.
Alpa Chino, played by Brandon T. Jackson.
Tran, played by Brandon Soo Hoo.
Tropic Thunder is a 2008 satirical action comedy film directed by Ben Stiller,
who wrote the screenplay with Justin Theroux and Etan Cohen.
The film stars Stiller, Jack Black, Robert Downey
Jr., Jay Baruchel, and Brandon T.
Jackson as a group of prima donna actors making a Vietnam War film.
When their frustrated director (Steve Coogan) drops them in the middle of a jungle, they are
forced to rely on their acting skills to survive the real action and danger.
Tropic Thunder parodies many prestigious war films (specifically those based on
the Vietnam War), the Hollywood studio system, and method acting.
The ensemble cast includes Nick Nolte, Danny McBride,
Matthew McConaughey, Bill Hader, and Tom Cruise.
Stiller developed Tropic Thunder's premise during the production of Empire of the Sun in the
spring of 1987, and later enlisted Theroux and Cohen to complete a script.
The film was greenlit in 2006 and produced by Stuart Cornfeld, Stiller, and Eric McLeod for DreamWorks Pictures and Red Hour
Productions as an international co-production between the United States, Germany, and the United Kingdom.
Filming took place in 2007 on the Hawaiian island of Kauaʻi over thirteen weeks
and was the largest film production in the island's history.
The extensive marketing campaign included faux websites for three of the main characters and their fictional films,
a fictional television special, and selling the energy drink advertised in the film, "Booty Sweat".
Tropic Thunder was released in the United States on August 13, 2008.
It received generally positive reviews for its characters, story,
faux trailers, and cast performances, with Downey Jr.
being the most positively praised for his performance.
However, the depiction of people with disabilities and the
use of blackface makeup attracted controversy.
The film opened at the top of the American box office and retained the number-one position for three consecutive weeks,
ultimately grossing more than $195 million worldwide before its release on home media on November 18, 2008.
Downey was nominated as Best Supporting Actor for an Academy Award, a BAFTA Award, a Screen Actors Guild Award, and
a Critics' Choice Movie Award, while both he and Cruise received nominations for a Golden Globe.
The film explores themes of vietnam, movie business, satire, parody, jungle.
The tone is lighthearted.